Who is Salt?
Salt is a action, mystery, thriller film directed by Phillip Noyce.
As a CIA officer, Evelyn Salt swore an oath to duty, honor and country.
Her loyalty will be tested when a Russian defector
accuses her of being a Russian sleeper spy.
She goes on the run, using all her skills and years of experience as a covert operative to elude
capture, protect her husband, and stay one step ahead of her colleagues at the CIA.
Her efforts to prove her innocence only serve to cast doubt on her motives, as the hunt to uncover
the truth behind her identity continues and the question remains: "Who is Salt?"
Evelyn Salt, played by Angelina Jolie.
Theodore Winter, played by Liev Schreiber.
Darryl Peabody, played by Chiwetel Ejiofor.
Oleg Vasilyevich Orlov, played by Daniel Olbrychski.
Mike Krause, played by August Diehl.
Young Orlov, played by Daniel Pearce.
Salt is a 2010 American action thriller film directed by
Phillip Noyce and written by Kurt Wimmer.
It stars Angelina Jolie, Liev Schreiber, Daniel
Olbrychski, August Diehl, and Chiwetel Ejiofor.
Jolie plays CIA operative Evelyn Salt, who is accused of being a Russian
sleeper agent and goes on the run to try to clear her name.
Originally written with a male protagonist, with Tom Cruise initially secured for the
lead, the script was ultimately rewritten by Brian Helgeland for Jolie.
Filming took place on location in Washington, D.C., New York City, and Albany, New
York, between March and June 2009, with reshoots in January 2010.
Action scenes were primarily performed with practical stunts,
computer-generated imagery being used mostly for creating digital environments.
The film had a panel at San Diego Comic-Con on July 22 and was
released in North America on July 23, 2010.
Salt grossed $294 million at the worldwide box office and received generally positive reviews, with praise for the action scenes and
Jolie's performance, but drawing criticism on the writing, with reviewers finding the plot implausible and convoluted.
The DVD and Blu-ray discs were released on December 21, 2010, and featured
two alternate cuts providing different endings for the film.
Salt was nominated for Best Sound Mixing at the 83rd Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of new york city, race against time, central
intelligence agency (cia), washington dc, usa, funeral.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending and intense.